

# **Artur Gomes**

Software Architect

- https://amng.github.io/portfolio/
- \* https://www.linkedin.com/in/amngomes

★ London United Kingdom

# **Profile**

Skilled and passionate software architect with proven experience in C++, Java and Python.

Been catching up with some of the current industry C++ standards (from 11 to 20) and reviewing some of the fundamentals in Data Structures and Algorithms, while preparing for the next position.

## Latest personal projects:

• Investuok: a website to access all the current investments and to calculate taxes for these investments.

# Competences

C++	6 years	Python	6 years	Java	3 years	Unreal Engine 4	1 year
С	6 months	Android	2 years	Javascript	3 years	PHP	1 year
CSS	4 years	HTML	4 years	Kafka	1 year	Cassandra	1 year
SQL	3 years	Docker	1 years	Kubernetes	1 Month		

# Experience

#### 2023-Now Software Architect

Inmarsat

Designed and developing as part of the team the Inmarsat Payload Control Center (Kernel), which will be used to control and monitor the payload of new satellites. Also designed and developed the Inmarsat testing framework which will be used to automate integration testing for multiple Inmarsat products. All this while supporting the current Inmarsat products. Also improved performance of one of the micro-services that decommutes telemetry by 4 times.

## 2020-2023 System Analyst

Inmarsat

Developed tool to convert telemetry into input file that is used to correct the clock drift on board of the spacecraft. Developed dump interpretation tool for a range of satellites in C++.

Developed Java and C++ example applications and a python script to control the Kafka services, as part of the migration of Corba to Kafka for I4S.

#### 2018-2020 Software Engineer C++

Amadeus/Astek

Maintained and developed several mission critical C++ back-end applications as a member of the Reservation and Departure Control synchronization team while contracted to Amadeus via Astek.

Highly contributed to the drastic reduction in the number of production issues (bugs, core dumps and memory leaks) from over 200 to around 20.

Fixed issues that had been in the backlog for many years.

Automated repetitive and recovery tasks using Python.

Reduced the run-time of tests of all our components by up to 75%.

## 2017-2018 Software Engineer, Games and Virtual Reality

Mimicry Games, Lda

Developed FingerPaint application for High Fidelity.

Worked on company VR project Ganbatte using Unreal Engine 4 which was released on the Steam platform after 9 months of development.

Successfully created all the single player levels, menus and websites for Ganbatte.

#### 2015-2017 Software Engineer

Consipere - Software Lda

Worked on the full stack of the company, first as an Android developer then on server side using python and finally developed some firmware for sensors.

Reduced synchronization time of between the android application and server by over 50

Developed firmware for FemtolO sensors using C++ for Arduino, which would collect data. This data would then be processed by Machine Learning algorithms to infer the type of movement applied to that sensor.

Re-purposed some pre-trained Machine Learning models and developed some tools to monitor the training using Python.

# Education

#### 2014-2014 Intensive German Course - Level A1.1

Faculty of Letters, University of Porto

Learned the basics of German Language during a summer intensive course. Achieved a grade of 17 out of 20.

#### 2009-2014 Masters in Informatics and Computing Engineering

Faculty of Engineering, University of Porto

Learned and developed programming skills and knowledge on Software Engineering.

Completed with grade 14 out of 20.

Wrote dissertation Procedural Generation Based on Affective Data which aimed to help game designers use procedural generation techniques to modify the gamers affective state.

#### 2013-2013 Erasmus - 1 Semester

Faculty of Engineering and Architecture, Ghent University

Information Security, Information Theory, Introduction to Operations Research, Software Design Project.

#### 1999-2009 English Learning

Academia de Línguas de Madeira (ALM)

Certificate in Advanced English (CAE) from Cambridge.